All right.
好的
So I think we have a better idea now of when we should and
我觉得现在我们已经更明白什么时候应该使用数组
should not use arrays.
什么时候不应该使用数组了
&gt;&gt; Yeah. But we haven't talked about how to
但是还没有讨论如何在代码中
use arrays in code.
使用数组
Like do each of these thoughts have a variable name?
这些变量有变量名称吗？
&gt;&gt; Well not exactly.
不完全是这样
So the entire array itself has a single name.
整个数组有一个名称
So, for example, we can call this array something like words.
例如 我们可以将这个数组称为单词
&gt;&gt; Okay. So the whole array is called words.
整个数组称为单词
But how do I get access to the string in each slot.
但是我该如何访问每个单元中的字符串呢？
&gt;&gt; Well each slot is called an element of the array and we can access each
每个单元都称为数组的元素 我们可以通过引用
element by referring to its numerical position or index in the array.
元素的值位置或在数组中的索引来访问每个元素
&gt;&gt; Wait, index?
等等 索引？
&gt;&gt; Yeah, so each position is numbered, It's kind of weird but
每个位置都有编号 我们以索引 0 开始
we start with the next zero and then move up to next one, two and so
可能有点奇怪 然后是索引 1 2 等等
on until we reach the end of the array.
直到到达数组的末端
&gt;&gt; Okay, so for an array of length seven we start at index zero and
所以对于长度为 7 的数组来说 从索引 0 开始
we end at index six.
最后是索引 6
&gt;&gt; Yeah, precisely.
就是这样
And all these numbers together are called indices.
所有这些数字都叫做 indices（索引）
&gt;&gt; Because the plural word for index is indices.
因为 index 的复数形式是 indices
Okay so it makes sense.
有道理
Now my question is how do we put values into the array in the first place?
现在我的问题是 我们一开始是如何将值放入数组中的呢？
&gt;&gt; Well, similar thing.
类似地
So we refer to a specific index of the array by using the equal sign
我们使用等号来引用数组中的特定索引
which remember is the Simon operator and we assign the value into that position.
等号是赋值运算符 我们将值赋到该位置
&gt;&gt; Wait I think I need to see this written down can I look at
等等 我需要看你写出来 我能看看
the code for this?
代码吗？
&gt;&gt; Yeah for sure.
当然可以
Anything for you, Kay.
任何需求都可以 Katherine
I'm going to walk you through some code samples now and
现在我将带你逐步研究一些示例代码
I don't want to give away the solution for the me walk up.
我不想透露出 Miwok 应用的解决方案
So I'm going to be using a different example.
所以我将举个不同的例子
So say we have an app where users can buy shoes online and
假设有个应用 用户可以在线买鞋
our app needs to keep track of which types of shoes are still in stock.
我们的应用需要跟踪哪些类型的鞋还有库存
So one particular type of shoe is really popular but
有一款鞋非常受欢迎
we only have three sizes left.
但是只有三个尺码还有库存
How should we store that information?
我们该如何存储这一信息？
Well since this is all related information about the same
因为所有这些信息都与同一双鞋
pair of shoes.
相关
We should keep them in an array.
所以我们应该存储在数组中
Later, this makes it easier to figure out which sizes are available
以后 我们将更容易发现哪个尺码还有库存
because we can refer to the single array variable
因为我们引用单个数组变量
instead of checking a bunch of separate variables.
而不用查看一堆不同的变量
So first we start off by creating the array.
首先创建数组
Since there are three sizes left, we'll create an integer array of length three.
因为还剩下三个尺码 我们需要创建一个长度为 3 的整型数组
Each element of the array will be one shoe size that is available and
每个元素都表示有库存的鞋码
the shoe size is an integer.
鞋码属于整型
I know the syntax can be a little tricky, it may look a little
我知道代码语法会有点难懂 看起来可能比较复杂
overwhelming because there's brackets and spaces all in weird places but
因为在各种奇怪的地方有括号和空格
creating this array variable is similar to how we've created integer and
但是创建这个数组变量和我们之前创建整型
string variables in the past.
及字符串变量是一样的
On the left here, we have the data type.
左侧是数据类型
Which in this case is an integer array.
这里是整型数组
It's the name of the data type which is the word int, followed by the open and
它是数据类型的名称 即 int 接着是左括号和
close bracket.
右括号
Then, we have the name of the array variable,
然后是数组变量的名称
which is shoe sizes available, followed by an equal sign then the new cue word
即有库存的鞋码 接着是等号 然后是关键字“new”
followed by the data type of the array again.
紧跟着又是数组数据类型
Int, with the open and close brackets again.
然后还是跟着左括号和右括号
But this time, notice that we put the length of the array inside the bracket.
但是这次请注意 我们在括号里写出了数组的长度
Now we have an empty array of length three.
现在我们就创建了一个长度为 3 的空数组
So if you ever wanted to change the type of data in this array,
如果你想更改此数组的数据类型
such as having it store Booleans to be a Boolean array,
例如存储布尔值 变成布尔型数组
then you would put Boolean here and here.
那么就可以在这里和这里输入 Boolean
Now we can assign values to each element of the array
现在我们可以根据索引位置为数组中的每个元素
based on the index position.
分配一个值
For the given array, the recalling shoe sizes available here.
对于给定的数组 我们称之为有库存的鞋码
We use the open and close brackets with the index number in the middle.
我们输入左括号和右括号 中间放入索引号
Example we've, and in this first example, we've assigned the number
在第一个示例中 我们通过使用等号
5 into the index 0 slot of the array by using the equal sign and so
将数字 5 分配给了数组索引 0
in this case the equal sign is the assignment operator.
这里的等号就是赋值运算符
Notice that there is no space between the name of the array and the brackets.
注意数组名称和括号之间没有空格
So when these three statements have been executed the array looks like this.
当这三个语句被执行后 数组是这样的
Later if you need to retrieve or access elements of the array use the name of
以后如果你想获取或访问数组中的元素
the array variable followed by the brackets and index in the middle.
则使用数组变量的名称 紧跟着括号 中间是索引
So this line of code here, will retrieve the first element of the array.
这行代码将获取数组中的第一个元素
And the result of this call, is 5.
该调用的结果是 5
Remember that indices start at 0 and increment consecutively.
注意 索引从 0 开始 并连续增大
So this is index zero, one and two.
所以这是索引 0 1 和 2
And similarly the result of the next line of code is 7 and
类似地 下一行代码的结果是 7
the following one is 10.
再下一行是 10
If you need to get the size of the array
如果你想知道数组的大小
write out the name of the array variable and then call .length.
则输入数组变量的名称 然后输入 .length
In this case this expression yields the number three for
在此示例中 该表达式的结果是数字 3
the three slots in the array.
表示该数组有 3 个单元
So here's some practice on how to use an array.
下面来练习下如何使用数组
There are many real world things that can be represented as an array.
现实中有很多事物都可以用数组来表示
For example, think of a soccer team with 11 players,
例如 足球队有 11 名球员
where each member has a different jersey number.
每个球员都有一个不同的球衣号码
We want to assign the number of their soccer jerseys at each
我们想要将他们的球衣号码分配到
place in this integer array.
这个整型数组的每个位置
Assume we've chosen four players for the roster already.
假设我们已经从球员名单中选出 4 名球员
We can store the jersey numbers of these four players at
我们可以将这 4 名球员的球衣号码
four different array indices.
存储在四个不同的数组索引处
So for the purpose of this exercise.
对于这道练习题
We'll put the jersey numbers in random spots of the array.
我们将球衣号码随机地存储到数组中的每个位置
Look at the different options of code in the provided gist and
请查看下所提供 gist 中的不同代码选项
pick the option that contains the code that would create the array above.
选出能够创建上述数组的代码选项